Hi guys welcome to my channel guys today I will
make a very helpful video because right now
I am inviting my parents to America
from India so recently I
started doing some research now they will
come to America for six months
on a tourist visa B1 BT visa which is available
from India to come to America
so I had to research that brother brother if there is a
health problem, medical issue then
how will it be resolved,
how will it be covered
because medical issues in America have a
lot of expenses so I
want to make this video from this very reason the topic of today's video
is visitor insurance or travel
insurance should you or should you not take it
for your parents so we will
talk about that today I have
done a lot of research so I thought of
sharing this information with you so guys today
in this video we will talk about visitor insurance
it is also called travel insurance
what is it where should it be bought from
why should it be bought what is covered what is covered
under it what is not covered
how much should it cost and how should it be bought  We will
discuss all these things step by step
in this video. Let's start
today's video. So the first topic is guys,
what is visitor insurance or travel insurance. So guys, as I
told you that now you guys are calling your parents
from India on tourist visa, so now they face
some problem in America,
let's know, let's not hope that
this happens, but in case it happens, then
who will bear their expenses? So guys, you will have to do it
right because you have parents, then if they have to go to
urgent
care, they get
bills of thousands and thousands of dollars
in an emergency. So, instead of
spending so many years of your savings,
if you take an insurance with a little coverage,
sorry, for a little premium, for a little
money, if you
take an insurance with a lot of coverage, that is called travel
insurance or visitor insurance and it is very
important, so this is basically an
insurance
which takes care of their unexpected expenses,
unexpected or any such things.  It covers it, it is
called travel insurance
or visitor insurance, so the second question
is where to buy it, should it be bought from America or
India and by the way this is
not just for India, if you are
coming from any other country, coming from any other country,
coming from a neighboring nation, it
is applicable to all of them as well, but basically if you are
coming to America, then in this video
I will just cover this topic that if
you are coming to America, it does not matter if you are coming from any other country, so
where to
buy it, buy it from America or
buy it from your home country before leaving that country, so guys, the most
I will
stress on the fact that you should buy from America
because here if you
buy from any other country, let's assume you
buy it from India, then it may be cashless, it may be that
they will say that we will cover it,
everything will be done there once
you bring it here and guys if it is not done then
you will be stuck with a
bill of thousands of dollars, it
could be a bill of $ lakh dollars, anything could be
possible  Hey guys, if there's a bill of $100,000,
who will cover it if it's from India?
If the doctors here say they do
n't accept it, which is a very common
scenario, they'll say they won't accept
this insurance, Indian
insurance. We don't accept it here. So,
where will you get $100,000 from? Guys, you won't be
able to get it. So, buy from here because
what will happen is that the doctors here will
talk about the insurance network here. There are two or three types of networks here, HMO, PPO, but
chances are high that more coverage will be
accepted here and the insurance will
cover as much as possible in case of any
incident. So, buy from America. The
third thing we'll talk about is why to
buy. I've already told you this in
short, you know, anything can go wrong
with anyone, accidents can happen. Who
knows, someone might fall from a ladder,
slip while bathing in the bathroom, or you know, there could be some other
health issue as well,
and it's possible that you might develop a new health issue
over time.  While living here, nobody knows,
I have a neighbor.
She had called her mom over, and
Aunty was absolutely fit and fine. But suddenly one
day I hear that Aunty had a heart attack.
Now tell me, nobody expects it right, but
these things can happen to anyone at any time. So
Aunty went to the ER, she had an EKG, she had an
angiography, now she has a bypass.
Now she is home
after staying in the ER for a week. I am pretty sure the
bill will be $100,000. At least that is the bill.
If you spend so much time in the ER and get
all this work done, then
why buy it for peace of mind? If peace of mind
costs so much, guys, are
you guys willing to spend your life savings of $
100,000 or
pay a small premium of $1000 to
protect that $100, I will
basically say this. Let's say how many
000 L it costs, $100, whatever.
In this video we will talk about the insurance you will buy. By the way, it is
only to protect $ lakh of your
hard earned money. We will
give you a small amount to protect it. Buy it for the peace of
mind you will get.
Guys, buy it for that and obviously without saying,
buy it for your parents' parents because health first, life is very important more than anything more than
money. Right, if I hope that nothing happens to
anyone, but in case it does, then
you should be
ready. Next we will talk about guys, how much to
buy and how much to buy.
Obviously, the more coverage the
better, but it also means it will be more expensive.
So you will have to decide
how your parents are currently,
how is their health, what is their age at this time, are they
below 70 or above 70,
because the older they are, the
more expensive the premium will be and the chances of
their death will be higher.
Also talk to them about their health.  Like I
talk to my parents right now,
I talked to them before making this video, both of them
are below 70, they have
not touched 70 yet, so
I was asking them how is your health
and obviously everyone has pre-assisting conditions,
some amount happens at this age, so my father has diabetes
and you know apart from that I was asking that
brother what else do you feel are you okay,
health wise you do
n't see any other problem in India, I
told them that you got a checkup done by a doctor once
before coming, he consulted the doctor, the
doctor also said that you are fit, you are
fine, so now if I want I can
take a little less coverage because
I know that they already have an accompanying issue
of diabetes, apart from that there is no other health
issue at this time and if you feel
that brother your parents are above 70 or
if you feel that you know
they are not doing well in their health, already
in India  So, it is also important to call them, so
then I would say that you should take more coverage,
and we will talk about that coverage in the next video,
how much should you take, so I would say
that first get your parents' medical
exam done once in India or
in your home country and ask
them how are you health wise at the moment, if
they are confident then obviously you can take a lower amount
and if you feel that they are
not confident then take a higher amount, it will be a
little expensive but remember peace of mind
and obviously I would also suggest that
before calling them here, tell them that all your
supporting medicines which you already take at
home, for diabetes, for
BP or whatever you
already take, bring them too because
those medicines will be available here also but they will be more
expensive, so why not bring them,
right, this is also an important point
for you, so guys, next we will talk about
what is covered and what is not  Covered, so
this is a very important point I would
like to tell you now that as I told you about
pre-existing conditions because at a very old
age things start happening
to the human body, so now like I
talked about diabetes, like my
father has diabetes, so
if anything related to diabetes happens to him
in the next six months, then it will
not be covered, guys because it happens like this while doing
diabetes and there is an
insurance which covers pre-existing conditions
also, but there are like twa, it is expensive,
double or triple expensive, so
if you think that it is very
urgent and you may take chances then
you people should take it, otherwise no one will cover pre-existing conditions,
no insurance will cover them, even after taking US, no
insurance will cover pre-existing
things, apart from that, many times it also happens that
someone's blood pressure increases due to LTs, and if
you file a claim, then it is possible that the insurance
people may also deny it saying that your blood pressure is
high because you  Diabetes
is a scam, many people say that
insurance is a scam, we can't do anything, but it is
very important to have peace of mind
and you can fight them whether your
BP is not due to this or not, but their job is to deny the claim
because you already have
diabetes, but it is your duty to fight,
so I would say that
apart from this, the pre-assisting thing, everything will be
covered, guys, accident is a very
important thing, if you fall from the roof of the LETS or if it is
raining while walking and you
slip and even then you break a bone, anything can happen,
right, so all those things will be covered, they will be
fully covered up to maximum, if
you have taken coverage of Rs. 0000 from LETS, then there is
also a deductible from LETS, we will
talk about that too, so you have a deductible of Rs. 500 from LETS
and your bone got broken
due to a fall and you went and got an X-ray done, got a
plaster done,
your expenses for all this will be deducted from $100.
99500 they will pay directly so
whatever new thing there is for Datchi will be fully covered
guys up to the limit up to the limit like
I talked about 00 you can take a limit of $ lakh dal
its premium will increase and
it will be fully covered up to that then but
remember pre-assisted if
you have BP then because of that your
BP becomes very high and within 24
hours if you have to go in emergency
then you will have to
take Datchi ment
you cannot live without it it does not mean that
your BP has increased you have taken medicine
you are going after three days then it will
not be covered guys then that regular pre-
assisted within 24 hours you have to
go to the hospital for that treatment only then that currency of
pre-assisting thing will be
covered guys now let us talk about
how to buy step by step process
because I will show you the entire process
I also bought it for my parents
and I went through the entire process  So
I want to share my information with you. In
case you
want to call your parents in the future, then guys, peace of
mind is very important. So let's get
started. I will show you how to get insurance.
Where to get it from. Step by
step process. Alright guys. Now I will
show you how to get insurance.
Travel insurance. Visitor insurance. This is
called there are only three
websites. Guys, from where you can get insurance. The
first one is IMG, IM Global and
IMG also call it. These are only three
websites and they are basically
resellers. Visitor cover.com and one is
inssai.com. These are three very famous websites
here. These are also called marketplaces.
We also call them resellers.
Basically, IMG will give you the plan
whether you buy it from here or from Vit Recovery or
from eBay. And guys, I will
put the place from where I am buying my insurance in the description. You have to
check it out. You will get the best price
through that link. And I
would like to tell you one more thing guys, if you  If you
buy from any of the three, you will get the same
price because there is
a law governing how much
price you get, no matter from whom you
buy, you will get the same minimum price
through all three websites and all three marketplaces. So I will show you the visitor's first
because I bought from this and I will
put the link of this in the description below. And
travel medical insurance gate courts, so your
destination country will be US because
you are coming to the US, which means your parents are
coming to the US. From let's enter the
information of my parents only.
My father is 68 years old, my mother is a traveler of
63 years and both are citizens of India,
so I will enter both of them as Indian. Let's
continue. Now I will pick a random
date because today is June 20.
As you can see, from let's
select the date of June 4. The start
date and end date are approximately 6 months, so let's make
June 29th November, it becomes 179 days
and these are both start and end dates.  Both are
inclusive, so the
insurance will start from the day you start
and on the day your end date is,
this insurance will
give end coverage till 12:00 pm at night, it will end till 12:00 pm,
this is what you will get quotes,
now I will show you how many
plans it has shown you here, it is
showing you a total of 14 plans here and first of all
you should turn off limited because we will
take only comprehensive plans because guys there are two types of
insurance plans, one is fixed coverage and
one is comprehensive coverage, so limited
means basically what happens in fixed limited is that
it will tell you that
any incident happens due to lets, be it a heart
attack, an accident, a fall,
anything, we will give you only $500 or we will
give you only $1000, even if your insurance is for Rs 1 lakh, then we will
give you the same amount no matter what your
incident is and that is very very useless,
your expenses can be very high
and you will get very little money
People buy them only in this case because they are very
cheap, so we will turn them off, guys,
I am not at all interested in them,
we will only take comprehensive, turn
on comprehensive. Now there are 10 plans
left out of 10, now usually I will do this, we will go in order of
price from lowest to highest.
Now I will show you what
options you should take, as you will
see here, plan features,
if you check pre-existing conditions, you
can select that too, but that is usually double
or triple expensive, so I will
not buy that, I will definitely buy this one, acute
onset of pre-existing coverage. Now you
will see that there are nine plans left out of 10, now
I will choose from these nine, I will
tell you how to choose and
as I told you, there is a price guarantee,
you can buy from any of the three websites,
insurance rates are always governed
by law, regulated by law, you can't find the
same insurance plan for a lower price anywhere else,
you will get the same plan at a cheaper price.  You will
not get it anywhere else because they are
governed by law, whether you go to any website,
any marketplace or re-seller,
now let us come and select from the lowest and choose
from the plans whether we want to take coverage
limit 50 or 100, from the lowest
you select 100 and now
comes the deductible, deductible 250 or you
can keep zero also, there are many options, 100 250 500
1000, now you have to see how much you are
comfortable with, this basic deductible basically means
how much money you will pay initially,
after that the insurance will start covering, if you
keep the minimum then you will
not pay a single penny, if you keep zero then you will
not pay a single penny, if you keep 100 then you will have to
pay 100 first, then the insurance will start bearing all your
expenses, basically there is a sweet spot of
250 and 500, so let us keep 500 and
see, so basically we have coverage of 100000,
500  I have taken a deductible and you
will see that this is only for non-profit traveler one
only, so this is a little expensive for one person,
we are looking at a plan for two people, so
you will see a plan for two people,
we will provide the same coverage, yes we will make this
also 100
and 500,
deductible 100 500, so the lower the deductible, the more
your premium will increase, the
amount you will pay initially, so I would
say that you should explore a little bit,
find out a sweet spot for yourself, what will be right for you,
and now we will start from the beginning, now let's see
Patriot America Plus, sorry, let's make this 100 again
and a deductible of 500, I am just
telling you to see once how to see the
plans and on what basis you
will select your
plans, now the second thing that you have to see while
taking any insurance, you have to
see that it should be a PPO network, like you will
see here, direct billing is written,
United Healthcare PPO Network  PPO
network is a very good network guys
in America if there is insurance through PPO
then
all the providers who take PPO,
whether it is
urgent or emergency, it will be accepted
everywhere, this PPO is a very good
network, out of which they have two PPOs
and United Healthcare PPO is the
best, like you will see United
Healthcare, this is First Health PPO,
so I will not normally prefer this,
I will prefer United Health
because it is the best PPO network among
these two options and you will see that
Covid-19 is also included, acute onset is included
and it is also extendable, if
I want I can extend it, it
is cancelable, if I want I can cancel it, this is
United Healthcare's PPO,
so all these options matter to me, now
I will go again and
see, I will check the coverage, only then I will
know how much price is there on which coverage,
once you have checked all the coverage, then
go back and tell me yours  Let's see
which one it is, like the second option is coming
but this is First Health People, I will not
give it, now the next option that is coming is
United Health Care PPO
Patriot America Plus Comprehensive and
all this is included, now it is costing me $2100. This is
almost six months
insurance for two people and there is a limit of Rs. 100000 per person, there is a
deductible of $500 per person,
so this is the option, we will click on more details in it,
now you will see
what all is included in it, urgent care
is included, emergency is included,
emergency eye exam is included, dental
is also included but it is a little, dental is
included only for about $300, medication
is included and there is also acute onset of
pre-existing Covid-19 etc. all this is there
and the biggest thing is United Health Care's
PPO, so this is the best option, guys, I will
say this  This is how you select,
according to your options, your coverage limit
and deductible, whatever you feel like,
you take a good insurance from the PPO network from there and buy it from there and
purchase it for yourself, so this is how you
purchase travel and visit
insurance from here and I will say again that
these three ultimately IMG will issue the
insurance to you and you
can buy from any of the three, all
three are same sellers, marketplace, all three are
similar kind of websites, it does
not matter, you will get the same price
because remember price is guaranteed,
law governs prices, not
websites and I like the visitor coverage,
I will put its link
in the description, you can buy from there,
click on it because
I myself have taken visitor coverage from them, so
I liked their support as well,
their support is the
best of all three, their reviews are also good, they have 4.6
stars,
you will also get their contact here
if you want  You can also chat,
their phone number is here, you
can chat with them from here if you want, you
can call them and I also called them
because I do
n't have their account, I
asked them how to do it, then
they told me on the phone that if you make a
direct purchase then all your policies will automatically be
created for you and
your policy will be included in it, so I
also liked their support, that's why I
am suggesting this and you will find the link
in the description, just for example,
I would like to show you that if you
also want pre-assisting from Lets, then
now you will see that you have only one
option, out of the nine options, only one is left,
Visitor Protect and you will
see how much the money increases, if we
go to the same coverage, then you will see that earlier
where it was showing me 2100 for two
people, now it is showing 4100 for two
people, so it has almost doubled, guys,
from 2100 to 4200  It is almost 4100 but
like almost double price  It's been done, but
pre-assisting is covered in it. And
I would still say that you should read their policies etc.,
like how much they cover,
it covers only up to 75%, but the
Pet America Plus that I showed you will
cover up to 100%, and you
will see that your policy maximum will be covered at 200%,
and for example, if you
go outside the network, then it will be covered at 80%.
First, I would like to tell you one more thing, when
you take United Healthcare PPO, whether it's
America or any other, and
United Healthcare PPO will be its provider, and there will be
billing. Then, by going to the United Healthcare
PPO website, you can actually see
which urgent cares are
in your network, so that you do
n't go to anyone else who is outside the network. If you
go to these networks, you will get more coverage,
and you will get that
information on the United Healthcare website. So, guys, this
was today's video. Hopefully, you learned and liked the
information
about travel and visitor insurance.
And how?  Let's take which coverage should we take,
everything, have your questions been answered or not,
ask in the comments, I will answer, I will
meet you in another good blog, bye guys
[Music]